# JOHN HOYSA

Austin, Texas • 512.914.0955 • johnhoysa.com

# Frontend Developer

Highly versatile frontend developer with extensive experience in HTML, CSS, Content Management Systems and E-Commerce environments and JavaScript. Excellent collaborative and interpersonal skills; able to establish lasting relationships with clients, designers, and developers. Easy to adapt and excel with deadline-driven projects and work well with creative teams or independently.

Skills and Tools

HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, GraphQL, Adobe Experience Manager, Magento, Craft CMS, GIT, Twig, JIRA, BitBucket, Confluence, Sketch, Figma, Adobe XD, style guides, WCAG, Svelte and React.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MRM - Remote

Frontend Developer, Feb 2021 to July 2023

Used Adobe Experience Manager and Magento to create unique user experiences to increase sales and customer loyalty in various international markets for clients. Worked with project managers, developers and QA to ensure quality code was delivered on time to meet project requirements.

- · Created accessible components and forms for AEM
- Integrated Magento data into AEM using GraphQL
- Created and Authored pages within AEM

MACSALES.COM / OWC DIGITAL - Austin, Texas

HTML / CSS Developer, 2015 to Dec 2020

Collaborated with a team of front and back-end developers to create, maintain, and update all websites within the company umbrella. Worked closely with stakeholders and marketing leads to build and migrate content into a CMS for manageability in an e-Commerce environment. Trained others on how to use and manage the CMS. Worked in tandem with UI/UX lead for creative implementation and execution.

- Developed and integrated a new, custom e-commerce platform in Craft CMS
- Managed and oversaw page and content creation of macsales.com
- Created and maintained main product website, owcdigital.com
- Ensured desktop layouts would translate easily to mobile views
- Created a single page web app for Used Macs configurator and My Upgrades within the e-commerce platform

JOHN HOYSA – Austin, Texas

Dev Consultant, 2005 to 2017

A variety of projects created for diverse clients, including Foda Studio, and Educational Service Center 13. Analyzed market trends, graphic design / web development tendencies, and specifications.

- Improved website usability and business results by revamping customers' sites to highlight products and services; increased interest and loyalty in brands, providing suggestions for design updates.
- Devised and implemented effective SEO strategies that enhance web design and responsiveness to attract audiences.

### EDUCATIONAL SERVICE CENTER REGION 13 - Austin, Texas

Web Developer & Project Lead, 2012 to 2015

Directed web development project life cycle, from defining goals / needs and providing technical insights to testing and delivery; adhered to client's requirements, including budget restraint and project scope. Designed applications focusing on delivering flexible, customize, and user-centric web pages; maintained communications with owners to facilitate management of sites and content.

- Trained users on WordPress, ExpressionEngine, and CraftCMS platforms, publishing tools, and site maintenance; empowering creation of educational and relevant content.
- Developed comprehensive training materials for teachers and school administrators using jQuery, Flash, and interactive PDFs.
- Generated wireframes, prototypes, graphics, and user experience while completing complex coding with the use of web programming languages, such as HTML, CSS, Flash, and jQuery.

#### NETSPEND - Austin Texas

Designer / Front-End Developer, 2011

Identified client's needs and goals to develop corporate and customer sites. Carried out A/B Testing in collaboration with NetSpend's team to analyze email campaigns and print collateral performance. Suggested design changes and enhancements as necessary to optimize website usability.

#### KINNSER SOFTWARE - Austin Texas

Front-End Developer, 2010 to 2011

Developed the front-end to Kinnser's web application with HTML/CSS in collaboration with ColdFusion developers.

# CTA ARCHITECTS ENGINEERS - Austin, Texas

Multimedia Designer, 2008

Continued development of CTA Architects Engineer's CMS, allowing management and maintenance of web page and its content.

### INNOVATIVE AFTERMARKET SYSTEMS - Austin, Texas

Multimedia Designer, 2003 to 2008

Utilized numerous tools and languages to generate engaging Flash and web-based presentations, print deliverables and icons for Innovative Aftermarket Systems.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Fine Arts with a Specialization in Photography Southwest Texas State University, San Marcos, Texas

Photography & Arts Program

Rochester Institute of Technology - College of Art and Design, Rochester, New York